raise.me 2017-05-12

# Privacy Policy - Raise.me

Effective Date: April 14, 2016

At Raise.me, we take your privacy seriously because your personal information is just that: personal.

Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy. **By using or accessing the Services of Raise.me in any manner, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy, and you hereby consent that we will collect, use, and share your information in the following ways.**

Remember that your use of Raise.me's Services is at all times subject to the Terms of Use, which incorporates this Privacy Policy. Definitions for any terms we use in this Policy that are not defined can be found in the Terms of Use.

## What does this Privacy Policy cover?

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") that we gather when you are accessing or using Raise.me's Services, but it does not cover the practices of companies we don't own or control, or people that we don't manage. We gather various types of Personal Information from our users, as explained in more detail below, and we use this Personal Information internally in connection with our Services, including to personalize, provide, and improve our Services, to allow you to set up a user account and profile, to contact you and allow other users to contact you, to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, and to analyze how you use our Services. In certain cases, we may also share some Personal Information with third parties, but only as described below.

As noted in the Terms of Use, we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for Raise.me's Services or send any personal information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 13 may have provided us personal information, please contact us at [support@raise.me](mailto:support@raise.me).

## Will Raise.me ever change this Privacy Policy?

We're constantly trying to improve our Services, so we may need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time; however, we will alert you to changes by placing a notice on the Raise.me website, by sending you an email, and/or by other means. Please note that if you've opted not to receive legal notice emails from us (or if you haven't provided us with your email address), those legal notices will still govern your use of our Services, and you are still responsible for reading and understanding them. If you use Raise.me Services after any changes to the Privacy Policy have been posted, that means you agree to all of the changes.

## What Information does Raise.me Collect?

##### Information You Provide to Us:

We receive and store any information you knowingly provide to us. For example, through the registration process and/or through your account settings, we may collect Personal Information (such as your name, email address, phone number), account information (such as a password or other information that helps us confirm that it is you accessing your account), demographic or other information (such as your school, gender, age or birthday, and other information about your interests and preferences), and third-party account credentials (for example, your log-in credentials for Google Plus or other third party sites). Any other information combined with your Personal Information will be treated together as Personal Information. You may have the opportunity to create a profile, which may include Personal Information, photographs, information about your academic and work history, your interests and activities, your use of Raise.me's Services and other information.

When you earn a Micro-Scholarship, you may be required to provide additional information, such as proof of identity (which may include a driver's license, passport, voting card or similar government issued identification), proof of academic and work history (which may include high school transcripts, standardized test scores, or references from teachers or counselors), or proof of financial need (which may include completing a FAFSA or CSS profile, and providing other family income documentation), in order to claim the award. Colleges which have awarded you Micro-Scholarships may share your application, enrollment and graduation information with us. If you provide your third-party account credentials to us or otherwise sign in to Raise.me's Services through a third party site or service, you understand some content and/or information in those accounts ("Third Party Account Information") may be transmitted into your account with us, and that Third Party Account Information transmitted to our Services is covered by this Privacy Policy; for example, if you log into our Services through Google Plus, your Google Plus profile information will be populated into your profile on Raise.me's Services.

All information entered by you is voluntary and at your own discretion, though certain information may be required in order to register with us or to take advantage of some of our features. If you provide such information, you consent to the use of that information in accordance with the policies and practices described in this Privacy Policy. Raise.me may, on occasion, send you notifications, information, materials, or other offers through e-mail, text, or other type of notification. Also, we may receive a confirmation when you open an email from us. This confirmation helps us make our communications with you more interesting and improve our Services. If you do not want to receive communications from us, please indicate your preference in the "Account Settings" page of the website.

##### Information Collected Automatically:

Whenever you interact with our Services, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser or device, which may include your IP address, geolocation data, device identification, "cookie" information, the type of browser and/or device you're using to access our Services, and the page or feature you requested. "Cookies" are identifiers we transfer to your browser or device that allow us to recognize your browser or device, and tell us how and when pages and features in our Services are visited and by how many people. You may be able to change the preferences on your browser or device to prevent or limit your device's acceptance of cookies, but this may prevent you from taking advantage of some of our features.

If you click on a link to a third party website or service, a third party may also transmit cookies to you. Again, this Privacy Policy does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties, and we aren’t responsible for their privacy policies and practices. Please be aware that cookies placed by third parties may continue to track your activities online even after you have left Raise.me’s Services, and those third parties may not honor “Do Not Track” requests you have set using your browser or device.

We may use this data that is automatically collected from interaction with our Services to customize content for you that we think you might like, based on your usage patterns. We may also use it to improve our Services - for example, this data can tell us how often users use a particular feature of our Services, and we can use that knowledge to make the Services more interesting to as many users as possible.

## Will Raise.me Share Any of the Personal Information it Receives?

We do not disclose your Personal Information, combined Personal and demographic information, or information about your use of Raise.me to third parties, except as set forth below.

**Information that's been de-identified.** We may de-identify your Personal Information so that you are not identified as an individual, and provide that information to our partners. We may also provide aggregate usage information to our partners (or allow partners to collect that information from you), who may use such information to understand how often and in what ways people use our Services, so that they, too, can provide you with an optimal online experience.

**Colleges:** If you are a Student, you may share your Personal Information with a College by taking certain actions on the Raise.me site, including, but not limited to, submitting your Micro-Scholarships for redemption, applying to specific programs and scholarships, or adding a College to your list of followed Colleges.

**Parents, Counselors, Guardians, and Advisors:** Raise.me may permit Students to share access to their accounts with parents, guardians, school counselors or other trusted advisors. If a Student permits such access, the permitted individuals will have access to the Student's account and Personal Information contained in the account.

**Non-Profit & Corporate Scholarship Administrators:** If you apply for a Micro-Scholarship sponsored by a non-College third party, such as a non-profit or corporation, your profile information may be shared with a third-party scholarship administrator to select scholarship recipients. The third-party scholarship administrator may contact you directly to verify your profile information, including, but not necessarily limited to, obtaining copies of academic transcripts, proof of financial need if required, or any other documentation Raise.me or the scholarship administrator requires to award the scholarship and disburse funds to you or your College.

**Sponsors:** If you follow a Sponsor, that Sponsor will receive access to your individual profile.

**Affiliated Businesses and Third Party Services:** In certain situations, businesses or third party websites we're affiliated with may sell or provide products or services to you through or in connection with the Services (either alone or jointly with us). You can recognize when an affiliated business is associated with such a transaction or service, and we will share your Personal Information with that affiliated business only to the extent that it is related to such transaction or service. One such service may include the ability for you to automatically transmit Third Party Account Information to your Services profile or to automatically transmit information in your Services profile to your third party account; for example, we may permit you to "like" content within our Services or "share" content to other web sites, such as Facebook or Twitter. If you choose to "like" or "share" content or to otherwise post information from or via the Services to a third party website, feature, or application, that information may be publicly displayed, and the third party website may have access to information about you and your use of our Services. We have no control over the policies and practices of third party websites or businesses as to privacy or anything else, so if you choose to take part in any transaction or service relating to an affiliated website or business, please review all such businesses' or websites' policies.

**Agents and Business Partners:** We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you; for example, we may use a service provider to send newsletters to our Users. We also may partner with or hire other businesses to help us grow or improve our Services and may need to share your information with them. Unless we tell you differently, our agents and partners do not have any right to use the Personal Information we share with them for their own purposes beyond their relationship with us. These third parties have agreed to hold and use your confidential information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**User Profiles and Submissions:** Certain profile information, including your name, location, and any video or image content that you have uploaded to the Services, may be displayed to other Users. Please remember that any content you upload to your public user profile, along with any Personal Information or content that you voluntarily disclose online in a manner other Users can view (on discussion boards, in messages and chat areas, etc.) becomes publicly available, and can be collected and used by anyone.

**Business Transfers:** We may choose to buy or sell assets, and may share and/or transfer customer information in connection with the evaluation of and entry into such transactions. Also, if we (or our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, Personal Information could be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party.

**Protection of Raise.me and Others:** We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information that we believe is necessary to comply with law or court order; enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Raise.me, our employees, our Users, or others.

## Is Personal Information about me secure?

Your account is protected by a password for your privacy and security. If you access your account via a third party site or service, you may have additional or different sign-on protections via that third party site or service. You must prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password and/or other sign-on mechanism appropriately and limiting access to your computer or device and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

We endeavor to protect the privacy of your account and other Personal Information we hold in our records and implement a number of security measures including password protected directories and databases to safeguard your information and SSL (Secure Sockets Layered) technology to ensure that your information is fully encrypted and sent across the Internet securely. However, we cannot guarantee complete security of the information you send to us and you do so at your own risk. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of User information at any time.

## What Personal Information can I access?

Through your account settings, you may access, and, in some cases, edit or delete the following information you’ve provided to us:

  * Name and Password
  * Email Address
  * User Profile Information, including images and videos you have uploaded to the Raise.me site

The information you can view, update, and delete may change as our Services change. If you have any questions about viewing or updating information we have on file about you, please contact us at [support@raise.me](mailto:support@raise.me).

Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to contact us to prevent disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for such third parties' direct marketing purposes; in order to submit such a request, please contact us at [support@raise.me](mailto:support@raise.me).

## What choices do I have?

You can always opt not to disclose information to us, but keep in mind that some information may be needed to register with us or to take advantage of some of our features.

You may be able to add, update, or delete information as explained above. When you update information, however, we may maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. You may request deactivation of your account by contacting us at [support@raise.me](mailto:support@raise.me). Some information may remain in our records after your deletion of such information from your account. We may use any aggregated data derived from or incorporating your Personal Information after you update or delete it, but not in a manner that would identify you personally. Deactivating your Raise.me profile does not guarantee that your information will be removed from third party records.

## What if I have questions about this policy?

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policies, please send us a detailed message to [support@raise.me](mailto:support@raise.me) and we will try to resolve your concerns.
